<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Interesting Bugs - Category - Luís Franco</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/categories/interesting-bugs/</link><description>Interesting Bugs - Category - Luís Franco</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:49:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ornlu-is.github.io/categories/interesting-bugs/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kubernetes deploy job failed but the service was deployed</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/kubernetes_deploy_job_failed_but_my_service_was_deployed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 19:49:34 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/kubernetes_deploy_job_failed_but_my_service_was_deployed/</guid><description>A while back, I was investigating a bug where my deployment job had failed, but the service had been deployed. At first I thought this was weird, afterwards I thought this was extremely concerning: had this happened before and I was just noticing now by accident? Since I did not want to have failed deployment jobs actually deploying my services, I took a closer look at this issue.
The situation What happened was pretty simple.</description></item><item><title>CIDRs and how they are handled by different systems</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/go_postgres_cidr_mismatch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:37:43 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/go_postgres_cidr_mismatch/</guid><description>I came across an interesting bug in the past few days. I had a very simple Go program that had a single purpose: it would take some user input, process that input, and then write it to a database. However, the program would sometimes fail, when given input that apparently was valid. And I thought that this bug was interesting enough to write about it, so here we are.
Understanding CIDR notation Before diving into the actual bug, it is fundamental that we understand CIDR notation.</description></item></channel></rss>