<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Luís Franco</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/</link><description>This is my cool site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 22:19:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ornlu-is.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Go Design Patterns: Functional Options</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/go_design_pattern_functional_options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 22:19:24 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/go_design_pattern_functional_options/</guid><description>The Functional Options pattern is a rather elegant manner of implementing a Golang struct constructor that allows for custom default values, which means that users of the API we are implementing will only need to specify the struct attribute values that the users deem that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take their default values.
For our example, let us consider the very simple use case where we have a package named person containing a Person struct, which will look like this:</description></item><item><title>Slim Docker Images via Build-step Containers</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/slim_docker_images/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 17:48:07 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/slim_docker_images/</guid><description><![CDATA[Docker images are supposed to be as small as possible, containing only what is absolutely required for the application inside them to run. In this post, I&rsquo;ll go over build-step containers and how to use them with Docker. For that matter let us consider an example Go application, nothing fancy, like the one given by the code snippet below:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 package main import ( &#34;fmt&#34; &#34;net/http&#34; ) func rootPathHandler(w http.]]></description></item><item><title>Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon 2: Web Scraping Movie Data</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/six_degrees_of_kevin_bacon_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 12:17:55 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/six_degrees_of_kevin_bacon_2/</guid><description>To achieve the goal of building a social graph for movie actors, the first step is to gather data. For that matter, I will be scraping data from the Open Media Database (OMDB) , which is a free non-commercial database for film media.
Other posts in this series Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon 1: Introduction Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon 3: Collecting the Data A plan for crawling OMDB The OMDB is organized very conveniently for my purposes.</description></item><item><title>Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon 1: Introduction</title><link>https://ornlu-is.github.io/six_degrees_of_kevin_bacon_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 23:47:08 +0100</pubDate><author>Luís Franco</author><guid>https://ornlu-is.github.io/six_degrees_of_kevin_bacon_1/</guid><description><![CDATA[Today I found out that there is parlor game named &ldquo;Six Degrees of Kevin Bacon&rdquo; and its rules are very simple: a player picks an actor and other players have to connect that actor to another actor via a film both starred in. This process is then repeated until Kevin Bacon is reached. The name of this game is a reference to the concept of &ldquo;six degrees of separation&rdquo; where, in the world&rsquo;s social network, every person is, at most, six acquaintance links apart from any other person in the world.]]></description></item></channel></rss>